Mohsen Shabanian

Full-stack Web Developer, with 6+ years of work mostly as a backend developer in C# and PHP developer. Also, I have experience with designing Web-Pages with JavaScript libraries (JQuery, ReactJs, NextJs, GatsbyJs), Databases (MS SQL Server, MySQL, MongoDB), .Net, Laravel, and JavaScript. Interested in working for international companies to meet challenges, learn new things, and share experiences and values.

Ramsar, Iran
(+98) 911-392-3310
info@MohsenShabanian.com
MohsenShabanian.com
GitHub.com/Mohsen12999
Linkedin.com/in/mohsenshabanian

EXPERIENCE

Freelancer, Full-time— Full Stack Web Developer

Iran, March 2020 - PRESENT

Peikresan:

Application for buying and delivering groceries.

 Develop with Asp.net core web API application with JWT authentication. Using SQL Server and caching.

 Front-end with single-page applications with PWA by React, Redux, JavaScript, and TypeScript.

- Define different dashboards based on user roles.

- Using external services for payment, location, and SMS.

- Using GitHub action for testing and deployment on the server.

Ketabche:

- Application for writers and readers to buy, read and write books and articles.
- Develop with PHP, Laravel, MySQL, and Passport library for Token-based authentication.

Amazon:

- Pet shop website to promote their service and show their stuff.
- Develop with PHP, Laravel, MySQL, and blade pages.

Also:

- Working closely with customers. Consulting about their requirements and technology.
- Support the websites, contact host providers, fix bugs, change experience, and add features with their opinions.
- Make and contribute to some open-source projects using Git in Github, Gitlab, and BitBucket.
- Little experience with Docker and Kubernetes.
- Automated test and deploy web applications with Github action.
- Deploy projects on Netlify, Heroku, Azure, and AWS.

APDR, Full-time— Co-Founder and web developer

Iran, November 2017 - March 2020, 30 months

- Worked with DevOps and Agile principles, BDD / TDD / DDD / SOLID / CI/CD, and other patterns and practices.
- Propose and present proposals for projects.
- Developing some prototypes for presenting to customers.
- Find, teach, interview, lead people, and make teams.
- Estimate time, budget, and technology for projects.
- Working with different Linux distros and configuring VPS for running multiple websites on a single server.
- Consolidated and recommended to clients about hardware requirements and negotiated their expectations

SKILLS

C#, .Net framework, .Net core, Entity framework, SQL Server. PHP, Laravel, MySQL, MongoDB. HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, JS-Library (React, Redux, Jquery, GatsbyJS, NextJS). Git, SVN, TFS. C/C++, Java.

CERTIFICATION

Certificate of Completion: C# Course, Sololearn 2016

Certificate of Completion: JavaScript Course, Sololearn 2017

Certificate of Completion: PHP Course, Sololearn 2017

Certificate of Completion: HTML Fundamentals Course, Sololearn 2016

Certificate of Completion: CSS Fundamentals Course, Sololearn 2016

LANGUAGES

Persian, English.

Amard, Full-time— Full Stack Web Developer

Iran, March 2016 - January 2017, 13 months

- Involving in analyzing, designing, and developing Enterprise Projects for big organizations and companies.
- Support and add features for old code base projects in Webform and MVC framework and work with legacy code.
- Help migration from Database-first to Model-first in Entity framework and reduce table and duplicate data.
- Making an Async table with MVC template, javascript, JQuery, and Ajax.
- Design and implementation of definable access levels for each user or user group.
- Experience TFS and SVN as a task and project manager and version control application.

EDUCATION

Islamic Azad University, Science And Research Branch, Kermanshah — Master of Business Administration

September 2011 - September 2014

Dissertation: "Investigating the effect of subsidy elimination on household electricity consumption using the genetic algorithm". Using evolutionary algorithms and artificial intelligence in Matlab for analysis and predicting electricity consumption before and after changing price.

Qazvin Islamic Azad University, Qazvin — Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical and Electronics Engineering

September 2005 - September 2009

Dissertation: "Control and change traffic signs via the SMS network". Design and make a device to connect a road sign and cellphone. We developed an application for an AVR microcontroller that is programmed to read, decode, and delete messages from a 3310 Nokia cellphone and send and display the message in a changeable sign on the roads.